alright let's get started welcome to the
好吧，让我们开始吧，欢迎来到
session on the powder &amp; pearl of
会议上的粉和珍珠
paralleled screams my name is Venkat
尖叫声我叫文卡特
Subramanyam we're gonna talk about some
Subramanyam我们要谈一些
of the beautiful things we can do with
我们可以做的美丽的事情
parallel streams what are some of the
并行流是什么
things we should keep in mind when we
我们应该记住的事情
start using parallel streams and and
开始使用并行流和
such things so let's get started let's
这样的事情，让我们开始吧，
talk about programming concurrency
谈论编程并发
programming concurrency is incredibly a
编程并发是令人难以置信的
very difficult thing to do
很难做
a lot of us including myself have
我们很多人包括我自己
started programming concurrency without
开始编程并发，没有
fully understanding the Java memory
充分了解Java内存
model and it turns out if we don't
模型，事实证明，如果我们不这样做
understand the Java memory model it's in
了解它所在的Java内存模型
the Bleak art to get it right one of the
荒诞的艺术使它成为正确的之一
probably the most scariest book ever
可能是有史以来最恐怖的书
written
书面
Java is programming concurrency by Brian
Java是Brian的编程并发
gets and before I read that book I used
在我读过那本书之前
to think that you cannot get concurrency
以为您无法获得并发
correct at all and after I read the book
完全正确，我读完这本书之后
I am thoroughly convinced now you cannot
我完全相信你现在不能
get concurrency correct anymore it at
获得并发正确
complex actually in all honesty because
实际上是完全复杂的，因为
it's just a way too many things could
这只是太多事情可以做的一种方式
potentially go wrong well it turns out
事实证明可能出错
that there are actually two different
实际上有两个不同
ways that we approach concurrency one of
我们处理并发的方法之一
them is what we call as a divide and
它们就是我们所说的鸿沟
conquer problem so you have a problem
征服问题，所以你有问题
you take n divided into two parts maybe
你把n分为两部分
and then you take these two small parts
然后把这两个小部分
and you make a decision whether you want
然后决定是否要
to solve that a smaller part or you want
解决较小的部分或您想要
to go ahead and divide it further and
进行进一步划分
you can keep going and in sequence
您可以继续按顺序进行
through this the other of course is what
通过这个，其他当然是什么
we normally call as parallel arrays so
我们通常将其称为并行数组，因此
you have a collection of data and you
你有一个数据集合，你
want to execute those collection of data
想要执行那些数据收集
in parallel
在平行下
well the parallel streams really fit
并行流真的很合适
into the second nature much more
进入第二自然
appropriately than the first one while
比第一个合适
you can try to use parallel streams to
您可以尝试使用并行流来
really do divide and conquer it is not
确实做到分而治之不是
that convenient or really a bill to
那个方便或真正的账单
easily do this it's really intended for
轻松做到这一点，这真的是为了
the parallel race problem when you have
当您遇到并行竞赛问题时
a collection of data you can easily
您可以轻松收集数据
throw them into parallel execution very
将它们投入并行执行
nicely that's where you get this really
很好，这就是您真正得到的地方
into so why does this parallel stream
为什么要这样并行流
really fit in well you have a collection
非常适合你有一个收藏
of data and you want to perform some
数据，您想执行一些
operations and you want to really speed
操作，您想真正加快速度
up the computation and you want to do
完成计算，您想做
that in parallel well let's take a look
同时让我们看一下
at how we could actually do this a very
我们如何才能真正做到这一点
simple example we'll start with right
一个简单的例子，我们将从右边开始
here let's say we have a collection of
这里说我们有一个
numbers in this case let's just say 1
在这种情况下，我们只说1
through 6 for a minute and I want to
通过6分钟，我想
perform a very very trivial
表现非常微不足道
transformation I'm gonna keep it
变革，我要坚持下去
extremely simple so we don't have to
非常简单，所以我们不必
break over you know a head trying to
打破你知道一个头试图
understand what the code is actually
了解代码到底是什么
doing so in this case I'm gonna simply
在这种情况下，我将简单地
perform a math operation we're given an
执行数学运算，我们得到了
element I'm gonna simply call a
我要简单地称一个
transform on the element and then of
转换元素，然后
course after that I'm gonna simply print
当然，我要简单地打印
out the element given to us so in this
排除给我们的元素，所以在这
case of course I'm going to just print
当然我要打印
it out as system dot out let's say print
将其列为系统，例如打印
illan and ask it to print it well we
伊兰，请它打印好我们
need the transform method again I'm
我再次需要变换方法
going to keep the transform but they're
要保持转变，但他们是
extremely simple so it's very obvious
非常简单，所以非常明显
what we are actually doing right here so
我们在这里实际上正在做什么
I'm gonna say transform is going to take
我要说的是转变将要发生
a number let's say and all that it does
我们说一个数字及其所有作用
is simply returns the given number so
只是返回给定的数字，所以
not a big deal at all as you can see so
如您所见，这根本不重要
we printed the numbers 1 through 6 right
我们在右边打印了数字1到6
here but of course this is running in
在这里，但是当然这是在
sequence as we would expect so I'm gonna
就像我们期望的那样，所以我要
put a little sleep here off let's say a
让我们在这里稍微睡一下
one-second interval and of course sleep
一秒钟的间隔，当然要睡觉
is just a method I'm gonna write here
只是我要在这里写的一种方法
and this is going to just give us that
这只会给我们
many milliseconds to sleep so what
要睡多少毫秒呢
what's gonna happen in this code when we
当我们在这段代码中会发生什么
run this little example let's just go
运行这个小例子，让我们开始吧
ahead and run this from the command from
向前并从以下命令运行
just to take a look at it and yes as you
只是看一看，是的，就像你一样
would expect it's taking about a second
预计大约需要一秒钟
to run each one of those values and it's
运行这些值中的每个值，
printing those values one at a time
一次打印这些值
sequential e so that's a pretty simple
顺序e，这很简单
trivial example as you can see but I
您可以看到一个简单的例子，但我
want to run this let's say fast or
想运行这个，我们可以说是快速或
imagine the transform is actually a real
想象一下转换实际上是真实的
computation not a dummy think that's
计算不是虚拟的，那是
returning number maybe it's trying to
返回数字也许正在尝试
figure out the meaning of life it's
弄清楚生命的意义
gonna take a lot of time and so if
要花很多时间，如果
you've got to pass these values and get
您必须传递这些值并获得
the results from it well how do you
结果如何呢？
really from these operations maybe you
真的从这些操作中也许你
want to speed it up by running that in
想要通过在其中运行来加快速度
parallel so to make this really parallel
平行，以便使它真正平行
there are really two approaches you can
确实有两种方法可以
actually take and one of them is to turn
实际上采取，其中之一是转向
the stream into a parallel stream just
流变成并行流
by using the word parallel stream and of
通过使用单词并行流和
course in this case it's gonna run in
当然，在这种情况下，它将在
parallel right off the bat let's see if
蝙蝠并行，让我们看看
it really does go ahead and run this and
它确实可以继续运行并运行
you can see boom it actually printed the
您会看到它实际打印的繁荣
result right there in one shot after the
结果在那之后一枪
second so that's running in parallel
第二个，它并行运行
when would you use this approach well if
如果什么时候您会很好地使用这种方法
you are the source of the stream it
你是流的源头
makes sense to use the parallel stream
使用并行流很有意义
at the source because you have the
在源头上，因为您拥有
ability to create a stream and while
能够创建流并同时
creating it you can say
创建它，你可以说
whether your intention is to run it
您是否打算运行它
sequential or run it to parallel but
顺序运行或并行运行
what if you're not the souls of the
如果你不是那个灵魂
stream imagine you are really receiving
流想象您真的收到了
a stream on your hand and you are the
你手上的溪流，你是
intermediary somewhere in between then
中间之间的某个中间
what do you do well the good news is you
你做得好，好消息是你
can do a dark parallel right here and
可以在这里做暗平行
you can convert a stream into a parallel
您可以将流转换为并行
stream by doing this as well as you can
尽力做到这一点
see right here so this is yet another
在这里看到所以这又是另一个
approach for you to be in between in the
介于两者之间的方法
middle of the pipeline and say that you
管道的中间，说你
would like to really convert this to a
想要真正将其转换为
parallel stream and you can do this
并行流，您可以执行此操作
again let's make sure that's actually
再次让我们确保这实际上是
working so go back and run the code and
工作，然后返回并运行代码，然后
you can see it ran it Rylee in one shot
你可以看到它一枪就跑了Rylee
before we go further
在我们走得更远之前
one small parallel you have to be very
一个小平行，你必须非常
very careful about because it's a bit
非常小心，因为有点
misleading when you are you know kind of
当你是误导你知道
not really thinking about what's really
不真正在想什么
happening for example you may wonder if
例如发生的事情，您可能想知道是否
there is a parallel call maybe there
可能有并行呼叫
should be a sequential call as well and
也应该是一个顺序调用
it turns out there is as you call that
事实证明，就像你所说的那样
you could actually use let's remove the
您实际上可以使用，让我们删除
parallel just for a minute from here it
从这里平行一分钟
is a sequential team to a stream you
是流的顺序团队
lead you know it you just said
导致你知道你刚才说的
sequential well is it running sequential
顺序运行是否顺利
well sure enough you can see that it's
很好，您可以看到它是
running sequential I won't wait for it
连续运行我不会等待
so the temptation here is oh this is so
所以这里的诱惑就是这样
awesome
很棒
we could take this map and run it in
我们可以拍摄这张地图并在其中运行
parallel and do the for each sequential
并行并为每个顺序执行
e well not quite so the last one
嗯，不太好，最后一个
actually wins so in this example this
实际上赢了，所以在这个例子中
entire pipeline is going to run
整个管道将要运行
sequentially even though we'd set
即使我们设置了
parallel in the beginning so you have to
在开始时平行，所以您必须
be very careful about it in the case of
在这种情况下要非常小心
parallel streams or in the case of
并行流或
streams you don't have an ability to
流你没有能力
flip back and forth between segments of
在各段之间来回翻转
the pipeline to run parallel was a
并行运行的管道是
sequential this is purely either fully
顺序地，这完全是完全
parallel or fully sequential so in this
并行或完全顺序
example notice I did say parallel in the
示例通知，我确实在
beginning but I'm saying sequential
开始，但我是说连续的
right after that in the in the middle
紧接着在中间
but when I run the code notice though in
但是当我运行代码时，尽管
this example it is still running
这个例子仍然在运行
entirely sequential II the map is not
完全顺序的II地图不是
running in parallel and that is because
并行运行，这是因为
this actually influences the entire
这实际上影响了整个
pipeline so from the beginning not just
因此从一开始就不只是管道
from that
从那个
onwards so we have to be very careful
开始，所以我们必须非常小心
how we use the parallel was a sequential
我们如何使用并行是顺序的
but also begs the question if it's so
但也要问的是
really easy to create a parallel stream
创建并行流真的很容易
then why don't they really make
那他们为什么不真正做
everything parallel that's a question
所有平行的问题
I've been asked several times by
我被问过几次了
developers my gosh look at that you can
开发人员我的天哪，你可以
just say parallel stream and make it run
只是说并行流并使其运行
parallel if it is so easy why didn't
如果很容易的话为什么不
they just do it for everything what I
他们只是为我所做的一切
call this a master switch and the reason
称其为总开关和原因
I call it a master switch is they made
我称它为总开关
it so easy up to the point where they
如此容易，直到他们
could have almost done it bid they
本来可以完成竞标的
didn't do it and then give you the
没有做，然后给你
switch and uttered one word at you and
转身对你说一个字，
that word is called think so they want
这个词叫做思考，所以他们想要
you to think about this before you turn
你转身之前要考虑一下
on that switch because turning on the
在该开关上，因为打开了
switch is really easy but the
切换真的很容易，但是
consequences could be really devastating
后果可能真是灾难性的
if you're not very careful about it so
如果你不是很小心的话
what are some of the things we have to
我们需要做些什么
be careful about we'll take a look at it
小心一点，我们来看一下
so in this case I want to know what
所以在这种情况下我想知道
threads are running our little code so
线程正在运行我们的小代码，所以
to understand what threads are running
了解正在运行的线程
our code let's go ahead and run this
我们的代码让我们继续运行
little code again sequential if you will
一点点代码再次顺序
but I'm gonna observe the thread that's
但我要观察的是
running this so I'm coming here an
运行这个，所以我要来这里
output let's say in this case we'll say
输出，在这种情况下，我们将说
transform and then of course we will say
转变，然后我们当然会说
the number we are transforming plus we
我们正在变换的数字加上我们
will output let's say thread dart
会输出，比如说dart线程
current thread and we can take a look at
当前线程，我们可以看一下
the thread that's executing this
正在执行此的线程
particular piece of code and of course
特定的一段代码，当然
when I go back and run this little code
当我回去运行这个小代码
as we would imagine it is telling you
正如我们想象的那样，它告诉您
that every single piece of that code is
该代码的每一段都是
being executed by the main thread
由主线程执行
there's no surprise there at all as you
像你一样毫无惊喜
can see I'm gonna suppress this
可以看到我要压制这个
particular output so we don't have to
特定的输出，因此我们不必
really look at it so given the element
真的看着它，所以给定元素
I'm going to simply say don't do
我只想说不做
anything with it so we can just see the
任何东西，所以我们可以看到
output of transform alone a little bit
仅转换输出一点
more clearly at this point so we can see
在这一点上更清楚，所以我们可以看到
that the whole thing is running in the
整个事情都在
main thread that's no surprise at all
主线程一点也不奇怪
but on the other hand of course what if
但是另一方面，如果
I'm going to go back over here and
我要回去这里
execute this let's say in parallel so if
并行执行这个，所以如果
I were to then do a dark parallel
然后我要做一个黑暗的平行
whether you do it dart parallel or you
无论是平行飞镖还是
create a parallel stream at the source
在源头创建并行流
really doesn't matter as you would
真的没关系，就像你会
expect when I go back and run this code
期望当我返回并运行此代码
you notice that all of them are going to
您注意到所有这些都将
run concurrently but in warth thread
并发运行，但处于运行线程
they're running in the for join pull
他们在参加加入拉
thread
线
as you can see but notice that almost
如您所见，但请注意，
all of them ran in full join pool but on
他们全都在全联接池中运行，但是
the other hand the first one did run in
另一方面，第一个确实在
Maine Maine is a really nice thread it
Maine Maine是一个非常不错的线程
doesn't sit there and say you all do the
不坐在那里说你们都做
work while I watch you it participates
我看着你参加的时候工作
in that as well in the in fact that is
实际上，这是
one of the reasons why the four join
四个加入的原因之一
pool usually has one less thread than
池中的线程通常少于
the number of course because Maine is
课程数，因为缅因州是
actually a participant in that as well
实际上也是一个参与者
but you are kind of looking at it like
但是你有点像
really why are we so strict about that
真的为什么我们这么严格
count we'll talk about that a little bit
算一下，我们再谈一点
later so let's talk about the order of
稍后，让我们讨论一下
execution I want to give you these
执行我想给你这些
things and print the result so going
并打印结果
back to this example right here let's go
回到这个例子，我们开始吧
ahead and suppress this output for a
并抑制此输出
minute let's get back to this and say I
分钟，让我们回到这说我
want to really print out the result so
想要真正打印出结果，所以
system dot out let's say print learn and
系统点出来，比如说打印学习和
then I'm going to print the results out
然后我要打印结果
of this right here well obviously in
显然在这里
this case when I go ahead and run the
这种情况下，当我继续运行
sequential e it is going to really
顺序e它将真的
preserve the order well keep in mind not
保持秩序良好，切记不要
all streams have ordering some streams
所有流都有订购一些流
have ordering some streams don't have
订购一些流没有
ordering how do you know if a stream has
订购如何知道流是否有
ordering or not well excuse me one way
点菜还是不好请原谅我
to know is what is the source of your
知道什么是你的来源
screen if you started with the list we
屏幕，如果您从列表开始
know list is ordered we know a set is
知道列表是有序的，我们知道是
not ordered so the source of a stream
没有排序，因此流的来源
may decide whether the stream is ordered
可以决定流是否已排序
or not you can also call methods in
或者你也可以在
between that might impose ordering on a
之间可能会强制要求
stream for example so it depends on
例如流，这取决于
whether an stream is ordered or not in
流是否有序
this example the stream is of course
这个例子当然是流
ordered we know that so when I go back
命令我们知道，所以当我回去时
and run this little code you can see
并运行此小代码，您可以看到
from the output that we get it's
从输出中我们得到的是
sequential of course but it's in the
当然是连续的，但是它在
same order as you would expect so the
与您期望的顺序相同，因此
ordering is preserved because we have
保留订单，因为我们有
ordered collection one through six but
下令收藏一至六，但
the question is what's going to happen
问题是将会发生什么
when we turn it into parallel though
当我们把它变成平行的
because it's going to run in parallel
因为它将并行运行
there is no guarantee of ordering so in
不能保证订购
this case as you can see it gave us
您可以看到这种情况给了我们
completely arbitrary order if you run it
如果您运行它，则完全是任意命令
again
再次
5 4 3 1 8 2 1 3 5 well here's a good
5 4 3 1 8 2 1 3 5好，这很好
news you got the result really fast but
新闻您得到结果的速度很快，但是
the bad news is the endpoint is really
坏消息是端点真的
not sequential imagine you're creating a
不连续地想象您正在创建一个
report it doesn't help the customer tell
报告它没有帮助客户告诉
them good news a guarded really done
他们是个好消息
as bad news it's all jumbled up go
坏消息全都混了
figure out that's not gonna invite a
弄清楚那不会邀请一个
good customer so how do you really
好客户，你真的如何
manage this well here's an idea there
好好管理这是一个主意
are certain methods that will impose
某些方法会强加
ordering on the execution so in this
在执行顺序如此
case I'm gonna say for each ordered and
情况下，我要为每个命令说
before run this let's really talk about
在运行之前，让我们真正地谈论
it I am NOT suggesting by any stretch of
我绝不建议
imagination that these are running
想像这些正在运行
sequentially no actually not they're
依次没有，实际上不是
actually running concurrently however
实际并发运行
the very last step says I will not run
最后一步说我不会跑
until the guy before me has actually
直到我之前的那个人
executed so it imposes ordering ordering
执行，因此强加了订购
doesn't mean sequential they do run
并不意味着它们可以连续运行
concurrently but it imposes an ordering
同时执行，但强制执行
at that particular point the point
在那个特定点
really here important is that the map
这里真正重要的是，地图
actually runs in parallel as we will see
实际上，我们将并行运行
in just a minute so if I go back and run
只需一分钟，所以如果我回去跑步
this little code example right now you
现在这个小代码示例
will notice that they are all running
会注意到它们都在运行
but notice no matter how many times I
但不管我多少次
run this the result is completely
运行此结果是完全
ordered even though it's running
即使正在运行也下令
concurrently and that is really good
同时进行，那真的很好
news that it has an order in postman
有邮递员订单的消息
well let's make sure that actually
好，让我们确保实际上
that's true so if I go back and turn on
是的，所以如果我回去打开
that print statement on the map method
map方法上的那个print语句
and run this again you will notice that
并再次运行它，您会注意到
they are running in actually different
他们实际上以不同的方式运行
order notice that from the output 1 4 6
订单注意从输出1 4 6
2 but from the output you have 1 2 3 so
2但从输出中您有1 2 3所以
the ordering is in the very last step
订购在最后一步
not in the execution of the map itself
不是在执行地图本身
they did run concurrently and they all
他们确实同时运行，而且都
kind of come to a grinding halt and say
有点停下来说
well I won't go until this guy before me
好吧，我要等到我之前的那个家伙
goes and that's when they are really
去，那时候他们真的
being you know in sequence if you will
被你顺序知道是否
so that is really a good news that you
所以这真的是个好消息
can have ordering there are certain
可以点菜吗
methods that will impose that kind of
施加那种
ordering for you if you were to use them
订购您是否要使用它们
so that's you can kind of have the best
这样你就可以拥有最好的
of both worlds in that in that situation
在那种情况下的两个世界
but we control the ordering but the
但是我们控制顺序但是
question really is how do things really
问题真的是真的如何
work when it comes to applying parallel
并行应用时的工作
you already saw this example I was able
您已经看到了这个例子，我能够
to use map in parallel similarly the
平行使用地图
filter will work in parallel but then we
过滤器将并行工作，但随后我们
kind of wonder will things like reduce
有点像奇迹会减少
work in parallel as well well to
并行工作以及
understand this let's go back to this
了解这一点，让我们回到这
example let's do the sequential e1
例子让我们做顺序e1
more time but this time around I'm gonna
更多的时间，但是这次我要
go ahead and call the output right here
继续并在此处调用输出
but in this case I will ask the very
但在这种情况下，我会问
last step to perform a reduce operation
最后一步执行归约运算
and we'll say zero comma
我们会说零逗号
total in this case let's go ahead and
在这种情况下，让我们继续前进，
say total comma element and we will call
说总逗号元素，我们将调用
a method called ahead which takes a
称为提前的方法
total comma element and returns the
总逗号元素并返回
result well this add method is going to
结果很好，此添加方法将
take two numbers and add them before I
取两个数字并加在我之前
talk about this in particular let's
特别讨论一下，让我们
understand what reduces actually doing
了解减少实际工作量的因素
let's say I want to total the age of
假设我要累计
everyone in this room starting with him
这个房间里的每个人都从他开始
isn't it's not smiling at this point I'm
这不是在微笑吗？
not gonna ask your real age so let's say
不会问你的真实年龄，所以说
we'll start with him so what are we
我们将从他开始，所以我们是什么
gonna do I'm gonna give him a zero as a
我要给他一个零
value that's age of everyone to his
重视每个人的年龄
right he takes his own age at zero two
对，他把自己的年龄定为零
it passes to the next gentleman he takes
它传递给他接任的下一位先生
the value given to him adds his own age
给他的价值增加了​​他自己的年龄
pass to the next gentleman and then I as
传给下一位先生，然后我作为
this data passes through the room the
这些数据通过房间
value that I get out of the last person
我从最后一个人身上得到的价值
in the room either is the total age of
在房间里的总年龄是
everyone in the room or overflow
房间里的每个人或溢出
depending on how old we are in this room
根据我们这个房间的年龄
but the point really is that we are
但关键是我们确实
going to have this sequential e the
将有此顺序e
value is going to trickle through this
价值将在此滴流
room and we get the result over there
房间，我们在那里得到结果
that's kind of what a reduces doing it
那是一种减少做的事情
collects the results and brings us back
收集结果并将我们带回
to one single value but I'm curious to
到一个单一的价值，但我很好奇
look at the ad itself let's go ahead and
看一下广告本身，让我们继续
once again remove this printout from the
再次从
map method but in this case I'm gonna
地图方法，但在这种情况下，我要
create a method which is the add method
创建一个方法，这是添加方法
which takes the value 1 and int value 2
它取值1和int值2
and all I'm going to do is output let's
我要做的就是输出，让我们
go ahead and say add + in this case will
继续说添加+在这种情况下会
output the value 1 and then we will
输出值1，然后我们将
output the let's say the value 2 and
输出我们说值2和
then finally we will go ahead and output
最后，我们将继续进行输出
let's say the thread information as well
我们也说一下线程信息
so thread dot let's say current thread
所以线程点说当前线程
and print it well if we do this it's
并很好地打印它，如果我们这样做
sequential execution at this point we
在这一点上，我们顺序执行
start with the value of 0 like I said
像我说的那样从0开始
he's gonna take his own age and add to 0
他要把自己的年龄加到0
and then pass it down so as a result
然后把它传下来
what you're gonna see in here is that
你会在这里看到的是
basically when you run this code you can
基本上，当您运行此代码时，您可以
see that in this case well actually
看到实际上在这种情况下
accomplish an error but we'll fix that
完成一个错误，但我们会解决
so in this case of course as you can see
所以在这种情况下，如您所见
it is going to sequential a run through
它要顺序运行
each one of these and and get you the
这些中的每一个，并让您
result out of this
结果出来
eventually so let's go ahead and fix the
最终，让我们继续进行修复
arrow right here be nice to return the
向右箭头很高兴返回
result here isn't it so let's say return
结果不是吗，所以说返回
in this case value 1 plus value 2 which
在这种情况下，值1加值2
is the result of the add function let's
是add函数的结果，让我们
go ahead and try this one more so in
继续尝试这个，这样
this case you can see that the ad is
在这种情况下，您可以看到广告是
being called in the main thread the
在主线程中被调用
value 0 plus 1 and then the result of
值0加1，然后是
that is one comes down here 1 plus 2 the
那是一个落在这里1加2
result of that is 3 comes down here 3
结果是3在这里下降3
plus 3 the result of that is 6 and then
加3的结果是6，然后
you can see that it goes through
您可以看到它经历了
sequential II but the question is does
顺序II，但问题是
it make sense to do this in parallel
并行执行此操作很有意义
let's go back to the example we just
让我们回到刚才的例子
talked about just a second ago I'm gonna
刚刚谈到我要
give him a 0 and say let's total
给他0，说总数
everybody's age in this room sequential
这个房间里每个人的年龄顺序
II but then I quickly realize gosh I
II但后来我很快意识到
don't have to really do this I am going
不必真正做到这一点，我要
to give every person on the left corner
给每个人在左上角
my left in this row a value of 0 and
我在该行的左侧值为0，
similarly everyone in this corner I'm
同样，我在这个角落里的每个人
gonna give a 0 and say why don't you all
要给0，然后说为什么不
every row total your age concurrent well
每行总计您的年龄并发
at the end of the first step I'm gonna
在第一步结束时，我要
have one you know several as many rows
有一个，你知道几行
as we have in this room I'm gonna have
正如我们在这个房间里所拥有的
that many totals on one side and that
一方面有很多总数，
many on the other side and I can then
在另一边，我可以
say hey the people on this row total the
说，嘿，这一排的人总共
values this way and people on this
重视这种方式，人们对此
column total the value this way in the
列以这种方式总计值
second step I'll have two values I can
第二步，我将有两个值
put them together and get the value cut
将它们放在一起并获得价值削减
you know immediately in other words we
换句话说，您立即知道
could do a divide and conquer of this I
可以做到这一点的分而治之
don't have to really do the sequential a
不必真正执行顺序
case in point in this case if I go back
在这种情况下，如果我回去的话
here and try to run this in parallel you
在这里，并尝试并行运行
will notice right away when I run this
我运行此程序时会立即注意到
code you can see that it is actually
代码，您可以看到它实际上是
running that all in parallel as you can
尽可能并行运行
see all that ad is being called in
查看所有正在调用的广告
multiple threads and you probably notice
多线程，您可能会注意到
there are more calls to add than before
有更多的通话要添加
as as I said in the case
正如我在案例中所说
I'm gonna call add on different groups
我要打电话给不同的组
of people and then collect it together
人，然后收集在一起
as what and the result is use whether
作为什么，结果是使用是否
you ran it sequential or concurrent the
您按顺序或并发运行
result is still 21 okay that is awesome
结果仍然是21还可以，这真棒
isn't it because I could run this code
是不是因为我可以运行这段代码
sequential II and the result is 21 and I
顺序II，结果是21和I
can run the code concurrently and the
可以同时运行代码，并且
result is still 21 that is wonderful of
结果仍然是21，这是很棒的
parallelism you cannot get a result fast
并行性，您无法快速获得结果
stir and say it's okay if it is not
搅拌一下，如果没有的话就可以了
correct right it doesn't make any sense
正确的权利没有任何意义
that result has to be still correct as
该结果必须仍然正确，因为
well when you when you do this so but
很好，当您这样做时，但是
you have to be very careful though the
您必须非常小心
value that you provide here is not an
您在此处提供的价值不是
initial value got to be very very
初始值必须非常非常
careful about it
小心一点
it is actually an identity value not an
它实际上是一个身份值，而不是
initial value for example or addition
初始值，例如或加法
zero is the identity value for
零是的标识值
multiplication one is an identity value
乘法之一是一个身份值
this is important to keep in mind
请记住这一点很重要
because let's say I'm interested in
因为假设我对
totalling my own age to the age of
总计我自己的年龄到
everyone in this room so I'm gonna say
这个房间里的每个人，我要说
20 right so you don't believe that okay
20对，所以你不相信这样
so I'm gonna start with that number well
所以我将从那个数字开始
20 plus 21 is the result we really want
20加21是我们真正想要的结果
in the very end so when it runs this of
最后，当它运行时
course you can see the result should be
当然你可以看到结果应该是
a 41 because the initial result was 21
41，因为初始结果是21
and we see that it's actually 41 but we
我们看到它实际上是41，但是我们
are in real trouble now because I did
现在真的很麻烦，因为我做了
not give an identity value 20 is not a
不给一个身份值20不是一个
value
值
I must mistook it as an initial value
我必须将其误认为是初始值
the result is catastrophic as when I run
当我跑步时，结果是灾难性的
this code this time the fight is no
这段代码这次打不了
longer 41 it is 141 don't bet on it
更长的41它是141不要打赌
could be completely different the next
接下来可能会完全不同
time because it is feeding all these
时间，因为它满足了所有这些
parallel values with the value of 20
值为20的并行值
which really doesn't make any sense so
真的没有任何意义
that is something we have to be very
这是我们必须非常重视的事情
careful again when we use parallel we
当我们使用并行时再次小心
really have to I mean it's no substitute
我真的必须说这是无可替代的
for knowing what we do in general but
知道我们一般会做什么，但是
especially with parallel that's very
特别是在平行的情况下
important and there's no point in
重要，没有意义
getting a really wrong result really
得到一个错误的结果
fast if you really want to get a really
如果您真的想获得一个真正的
fast
快速
real if you really want to get a result
如果您真的想要获得结果，则为真
really fast and you don't care about
真的很快，你不在乎
whether it's right or not you really
不管是不是真的
want to go back and program in C++ isn't
想回去用C ++编程不是
it so absolutely this is not the reason
所以这绝对不是原因
to do it so we really want to make sure
做到这一点，所以我们真的想确保
that we get the result correctly as well
我们也可以正确得到结果
not just faster in this particular case
在这种情况下不仅更快
so when we go back and run this if of
所以当我们返回并运行
course in this case the result is still
当然，在这种情况下结果仍然是
going to be the same because I'm
会一样，因为我
providing an identity value well then
然后提供一个身份值
the question is if I really want to add
问题是我是否真的要添加
my eight why do well sure that's not a
我的八个为什么要做好那不是
big deal because I can come back here
没关系，因为我可以回到这里
and add it at the very end of this
并在此末尾添加
particular well of course in this case
在这种情况下当然特别好
correct something to keep in mind what
纠正一些事情要记住什么
you're sending in as an initial value
您将作为初始值发送
makes a huge difference
有很大的不同
but that begs the question we've been
但这引出了我们一直以来的疑问
looking at these threads
看着这些线程
what are these threads really do what do
这些线程到底在做什么？
they really use we really want to
他们真的使用我们真的想要
understand it so how many threads do we
了解它，所以我们有多少个线程
get without doing any single work and to
一劳永逸
understand this let's look at a little
了解这一点，让我们看一下
bit of an output right here let's get
一点输出就在这里
back to this little math function and I
回到这个小数学函数，我
would say for each in this case given an
在这种情况下，每个人都会说
element
元件
I just want to simply suppress the
我只想简单地压制
output let's go back to the map method
输出让我们回到map方法
transform method and print that result
转换方法并打印结果
out so this will give us a little bit of
出来，这样可以给我们一点点
an idea how many threads are gonna run
一个想法，将要运行多少个线程
for us now when I go back here let's go
现在回到我们这里去吧
ahead and take a values one through
向前并通过一个价值观
seven let's say eight nine and ten but
七个，比方说八个九个和十个
I'm going to repeat this one more time
我将再重复一次
in here let's say I have the values just
在这里，假设我具有这些值
repeated so I have these values even if
重复，所以我有这些价值观，即使
we want to really say let's say this is
我们要说的真的是
11 and 12 and 13 I can have these little
11和12和13我可以拥有这些小东西
values being provided so that we can see
提供值，以便我们可以看到
how many threads are gonna run
要运行多少个线程
concurrently well it turns out the way
同时很好的结果
this actually works is that by default
这实际上是默认情况下
you get as many threads as the number of
您得到的线程数与
cores on your machine so I want to know
核心在您的计算机上，所以我想知道
how many cores I have on my machine so
我的机器上有多少个核心
let's go ahead and remove this just
让我们继续删除此
momentarily and I'm gonna go back here
暂时，我要回到这里
and say output run time dart runtime so
并说输出运行时dart运行时
in this case let's say run time and what
在这种情况下，我们说运行时间以及什么
are we going to ask for in this case I
在这种情况下我们要问我吗
don't remember this method right now but
现在不记得这种方法了，但是
available processors right so I want to
可用的处理器，所以我想
know how many processors are available
知道有多少个处理器可用
and it tells me there are eight
告诉我有八个
processors available on my machine so
机器上可用的处理器，因此
that is a way for you to find out how
这是您了解如何
many cores are available it is a blatant
有很多核心可用，这是公然的
false information by the way it's a lot
虚假信息很多
I don't have eight cores on my machine
我的机器上没有八个核心
but that's what it tells me so in this
但这就是它告诉我的
case of course it tells me that I have
当然，这告诉我
eight cores I have actually four but it
八个核心我实际上有四个，但是
just wants to calculate as eight well
只想算八
that's fine but it's going to give me a
很好，但这会给我一个
total of eight threads what remember
共有八个线程还记得
main is part of that as well so the
主要也是其中的一部分，所以
formed common fork/join pool contains a
形成的公共分叉/联接池包含一个
total of seven threads when my machine
当我的机器共有七个线程
has eight cores how do I notice well
有八个核心我该如何注意
here's an a little example we could
这是一个小例子，我们可以
simply go ahead and say over here for
只是继续说在这里
join puh
加入puh
a dart common-pool that's the way you
飞镖公共游泳池就是你的方式
can get access to the common pool and
可以访问公共池，并且
then you can ask for the details from it
然后您可以从中索取详细信息
obviously to do you use this I need the
显然您要使用这个我需要
java.util concurrent so I'm gonna bring
java.util并发，所以我要带
that in here so here is concurrent and
在这里，所以这里是并发的
what am I gonna do at this point so
我现在要做什么
notice I'm gonna ask him for details
注意我要问他细节
about the common pool when I go back and
关于我回去时的公共泳池
run this little code it tells me have 8
运行这个小代码，它告诉我有8
cores but note this right here it says
核心，但请注意这里
parallelism is 7
并行度是7
well that's because 7 plus 1 is 8 which
那是因为7加1是8
is the total number of course on my
是我的课程总数
machine main being the other participant
机器主体是其他参与者
of this particular Club so that is
这个特定俱乐部的
basically what we are seeing here the 4
基本上我们在这里看到的是4
join pool is being used now here's a way
现在正在使用连接池，这是一种方法
to think about it because of the nature
考虑自然
in which these things work this way how
这些东西以这种方式工作的方式
is this going to be scheduled across
这将被安排在
those different threads as you would
那些不同的线程
imagine I have 20 elements on my hand
想象我手上有20个元素
I'm gonna schedule those 20 elements
我要安排这20个元素
over 8 cores on my machine so how many
我机器上有8个以上的内核
batches are we looking at approximately
我们正在分批查看
give or take three batches so 8 16 and
给或取三批，所以8 16和
the remaining in to achieve the 20 we
剩下的要达到20
can actually see this in motion here
实际上可以在这里看到它的运动
let's go ahead and run this up and burst
让我们继续运行并爆发
of call here's the first after call well
的通话，这是通话后的第一个通话
actually if it compiles that is so let's
实际上，如果它可以编译，那就让我们
go ahead and remove this output right
继续并正确删除此输出
here and try this again so we're gonna
在这里，再试一次，我们要
see a first burst of the call right here
在这里看到第一通电话
so let's see if that's true so here is
所以让我们看看这是真的，所以这是
burst one burst 2 verse 3 done so that's
爆破1爆破2经文3
in 3 bursts as you can see the output
可以看到3个突发
came through and the reason for three
来了，三个原因
bursts in fact a little bit easier if I
事实上，如果我突然爆发
remove the thread details for you so
为您删除线程详细信息，以便
pardon me here while I make it a little
我在这儿请稍等一下
bit more easier to see with a little
一点点就更容易看到
concise output so here we go that's
简洁的输出，所以我们在这里
burst one burst 2 verse 3 and done so
爆破一首2节经文3首
that's obviously scheduling across those
那显然是跨那些安排的
those eight different is that are
那八个不同是
available on my system but that brings
在我的系统上可用，但这带来了
up the question why so careful about
提出问题，为什么要如此小心
default threads why can't we just go
默认线程为什么我们不能走
wild with it
疯狂
we'll see why there's reason in just a
我们将看到为什么只有一个原因
second so when you're doing parallel
第二，所以当你做并行时
streams you have to be very careful they
流你必须非常小心他们
didn't select number of cores equal to
没有选择等于的内核数
number of threads by default arbitrarily
默认情况下任意线程数
they are very very clever they
他们非常非常聪明
said if anything were to go wrong they
说如果有什么毛病，他们
want you to take the blame not them
希望你不要责怪他们
right which is only what I would do if I
对的，这只是我要做的
was designing libraries I don't want to
在设计我不想的库
be blamed for decisions I make I want to
我做的决定要怪我
be very safe in decisions I make so the
我做的决定非常安全，所以
safest decision I can make is to give
我能做出的最安全的决定是
you as many threads as number of course
您与课程数量一样多的线程
but that begs the question why in the
但这引出了一个问题，为什么在
world is that safe well I'm gonna give
我会给世界那么安全
you a really silly example imagine there
你是一个非常愚蠢的例子，想象在那里
are monks and you know how monks are the
是和尚，你知道和尚如何
most polite people right imagine there
最有礼貌的人对吗？
are four monks and there are two
有四个和尚，有两个
treadmills so the four decide to go to a
跑步机，所以四个决定去
gym so they go to the gym and two months
健身房，所以他们去健身房和两个月
get on the treadmill and you know how
上跑步机，你知道如何
monks are very polite they get on the
和尚非常有礼貌他们上
treadmill and they look down and say oh
跑步机，他们低头说哦
my dear God you both are waiting how
亲爱的上帝，你们俩都在等待
rude of me to be on the treadmill and
我在跑步机上无礼
they immediately get down from the
他们立即从
treadmill the other two monks get on the
跑步机上，其他两个和尚上
treadmill and what do they do they say
跑步机，他们说什么
how rude of me when you are awaiting
你在等我时多么无礼
their I am on the treadmill and the
他们在跑步机上
monks never exercise this is why it's
和尚从不运动，这就是为什么
good to be rude in life sometimes isn't
生活中有时会表现出无礼的好习惯
it no just kidding
这不只是在开玩笑
but the point really is this is exactly
但关键是这确实是
what threats are going to do if your
如果您的威胁会做什么
threads are computation intensive they
线程是计算密集型的
behave that like like those monks
像那些和尚一样
they're going to get on the CPU in this
他们将在这个CPU上
case the ones below are the ones pulling
情况如下
it down so it's kind of little
它下来所以有点
controversial in this case but the
在这种情况下有争议，但
threads waiting say hey you get off it's
线程等待说嘿，你下车了
my turn and the threads running on the
轮到我了，线程在
CPU say but I have work to do I don't
CPU说，但我有工作要做，我没有
care it's my turn get off the CPU so
关心轮到我下车了，所以
they eat the CPU only for these two get
他们只为这两个吃掉CPU
on and guess what the ones that got off
继续猜测下车的是什么
do they turn around say you get off now
他们转过身说你现在下车吗
and they're going to trash each other
他们会互相浪费
we're gonna lose performance we're not
我们会失去表现，我们不会
careful so the model of the story is
小心，所以故事的模式是
this so the number of threads that you
这样线程数就可以了
always want to give is less than or
总是想给小于或
equal to and then you can do a little
等于然后你可以做一点
little quick formula you can say on the
你可以在上面说的小快速公式
numerator is the number of cores on your
分子是您的核心数
machine we'll start with this and then
机器，我们将从此开始，然后
one - well then I'm gonna say this is
一个-好吧，我要说的是
called the blocking factor so let's say
叫做阻碍因素，所以说
what is a blocking factor so if I am the
什么是阻碍因素，所以如果我是
blocking factor is zero less than or
阻塞因子小于零或
equal to the blocking factor less than
等于阻塞因子小于
one if I'm a computation intensive
如果我是计算密集型的人
thread then what happens if I'm a
线程然后如果我是
competition item in terms of Ted I'm
根据Ted我的比赛项目
running and running and running
运行，运行，运行
I have no
我没有
opportunity to take a break I have
我有休息的机会
nothing to sleep for well my blocking
没有什么好睡觉的
factor is zero if I'm an i/o intensive
如果我是I / O密集型，系数为零
thread I want to write to a database I
我想写入数据库的线程
want to read from a database I want to
想从数据库中读取我想
make a call to a remote system I want to
拨打我要的远程系统
write to a log file I want to open files
写入日志文件我要打开文件
and every one of these opportunities is
这些机会中的每一个都是
when I'm gonna say CPU you take it easy
当我要说CPU时，请放轻松
I'm waiting on this file to kick in and
我正在等待这个文件的开始
bring the data to me and what is the CPU
带给我数据，什么是CPU
gonna do the CPU is like gosh I don't
要去做CPU就像我不喜欢
have any work to do you are sleeping at
你有什么事要做
the wheel right now you're going to go
轮子，现在你要走了
get the data well you might as well work
很好地获取数据，您可能会工作得很好
on another thread that requires
在另一个需要的线程上
processing when I don't have anything to
当我没有什么要处理时
do so if you have an i/o thread a task
如果您有I / O线程，请执行此操作
you can have more threads using your CPU
您可以使用CPU拥有更多线程
more tasks using your CPU at that point
届时将使用您的CPU执行更多任务
so if I have a task which is sleeping
所以如果我有一个正在睡觉的任务
for let's say in this case let's work
因为在这种情况下，让我们工作
the formula I am a computation intensive
我需要大量计算的公式
thread which means the blocking factor
线程，这意味着阻塞因素
the blocking factor is equal to zero
阻塞因子等于零
isn't it then the number of threads I
是不是然后我的线程数
want to really create is less than or
要真正创建小于或
equal to number of core because 1 minus
等于核心数，因为1减
0 is 1 in the denominator but if I'm an
分母中的0是1，但如果我是
i/o intensive let's say with let's say
I / O密集型让我们一起说
blocking factor of let's say 0.5 then
假设阻挡因子为0.5
the number of threads that you can
您可以使用的线程数
provide me is less than or equal to 2
只要我小于或等于2
times the number of cores in reality if
乘以实际的核数，如果
I'm sleeping most of the time you can
我大部分时间都在睡觉
give me more cores as assuming of course
当然给我更多的核心
that there is enough work to do right
有足够的工作要做正确的事
and of course if the blocking factor is
当然，如果阻碍因素是
1 that's a deadlock you don't want to go
1那是您不想去的僵局
there so absolutely you can give more
那里绝对可以给你更多
threads if I am i/o intensive
如果我是I / O密集的线程
fewer threads if I am computation
如果我在计算，线程数更少
intensive now you know why they chose
精读现在你知道他们为什么选择
the number of threads default is equal
默认的线程数等于
to number of course because that's a
当然，因为那是一个
very safe bet because they don't know
非常安全的赌注，因为他们不知道
what you're doing they cannot predict
你在做什么，他们无法预测
what you're doing so the safest bet is
您正在做的最安全的选择是
to say hey your computation intensive
说嘿你的计算量大
but what if I am NOT well then you can
但是如果我不舒服怎么办
vary the number of threads you want to
改变您想要的线程数
use well here's the formula we just
很好地使用这是我们刚才的公式
looked at to decide the number of
看着决定数量
threads but how do you really configure
线程，但您如何真正配置
the number of threads that you want to
您想要的线程数
use in your application this is a
在您的应用程序中使用这是一个
dangerous setting be careful using it
危险环境请小心使用
but this setting simply says - V at the
但此设置只是说-
jvm level
JVM级别
Java dot util dot concurrent dot for
Java点util点并发点
joint pooled our common dot parallelism
联合我们共同的点并行性
I love this property finally something
我终于爱上了这家酒店
longer than my name so as you can see
比我的名字长，如你所见
here you can specify this property and
在这里您可以指定此属性，
ask it to use this right here so how do
请它在这里使用此权限，怎么办
I use this I'm a little lazy person I'm
我用这个我有点懒惰
not gonna really tight this all manually
不会真的将所有这些手动收紧
so I'm gonna show you the example by
所以我要给你看这个例子
using little script where I'm gonna use
在我要使用的地方使用小脚本
this thread so here is a run config I
这个线程，所以这是一个运行配置
have written for myself where that is
为自己写的那是哪里
setting that property as you can see the
设置该属性，如您所见
run configures doing it so I don't have
运行配置这样做，所以我没有
to manually mess with this if I run the
如果我运行
run method just now as we saw it's using
就像我们看到的那样运行方法
the default number of threads
默认线程数
that's burst one burst two birth three
那是一胎二胎三胎
as you can see but if I do run config on
如您所见，但如果我确实在
the other hand and give it a hundred
另一方面，给它一百
threads that's burst one and I'm done as
爆裂的线程，我完成了
you can see because it gave us a hundred
你可以看到，因为它给了我们一百
threads to run not just one one set of
不仅要运行一组线程
eight threads be very careful using this
八个线程使用时要非常小心
feature because it changes the settings
功能，因为它会更改设置
on your entire JVM not something you
在整个JVM上，而不是您
want to do so so quickly without
想要如此迅速地做而没有
thinking also if you're using or one
还考虑是否正在使用或一个
other thing I heard from clients quite
我从客户那里听到的另一件事
often is they'd be using a third-party
通常是他们会使用第三方
container don't mess with this when
容器不要在这个时候弄乱
you're dealing with third-party
您正在与第三方打交道
containers third-party containers are
容器第三方容器是
mostly intended so they can take away
主要是为了让他们可以带走
the threading from us so this is kind of
来自我们的线程，所以这有点
going contrary to that be careful about
与之相反的是要小心
it you can also configure this
你也可以配置它
programmatically as well how do you
以编程方式以及您如何
change this programmatically if you want
如果需要，以编程方式更改此设置
to change this programmatically what you
以编程方式更改此内容
can do in here is you can create your
可以在这里做的是，您可以创建自己的
own for join pool so for join pull let's
拥有加入池，因此加入连接让我们
say over here pool is equal to new for
说在这里池等于新的
join pool are 50 let's say and then I'm
加入游泳池，让我们说50，然后我
gonna say pool Dart
要说池镖
shutdown this is one of my things
关闭这是我的事情之一
usually I want to shut it down as soon
通常我想尽快将其关闭
as I create it and this is going to
当我创建它，这将
require that you handle exception we'll
要求您处理例外情况，我们将
come back to that in just a minute and
再过一分钟再说
then I'm going to say over here a pool a
那我要在这里说一个游泳池
dart await termination and then I'm
飞镖等待终止，然后我
gonna say let's say 10 comma time a time
要说一次10次逗号
unit a dart let's say seconds so I'm
一支飞镖，说几秒钟，所以我
gonna give it 10 seconds for it to
要给它10秒钟
finish up all this now within does what
现在完成所有这些工作
I could do is I could say pool darts
我能做的就是说可以飞镖
submit and within the submit I could
提交，在提交中，我可以
simply go ahead and say
只是继续说
that I want to perform that operation
我想要执行该操作
right there in parallel of course but
当然在那里平行，但是
notice the call to this parallel comes
注意对这个并行的调用
from within this right here and as a
从这里，在这里
result because I'm calling this in a
结果，因为我在
four join pole this is going to run in
四个连接杆，这将在
the pool which is native to that
那是本地的
particular call and it's going to do
特别的电话，它将要做
that of course this won't work at the
那当然不会在
moment it complains that I have to deal
当它抱怨我必须处理
with inter interrupted exception there's
除间断异常外，
a game we always play with Java right
我们一直都在用Java玩的游戏
you write some code in Java says you
你用Java写一些代码说你
will handle the exception and you as a
将处理异常，您作为
programmer show who's in power by
程序员展示谁在掌权
putting throws exception right so this
放抛出异常权，所以这
is very awesome so basically in this
真的很棒，所以基本上
case you kind of say all right I'm
如果你说好吧，我是
dealing with that so in this case what's
处理这种情况，这是什么
the thread notice it's no longer the
线程注意到它不再是
common pool it's a fourth line pool we
公共游泳池，这是我们的四线游泳池
just created right off here that's what
刚创建就在这里
we are really doing at this point so
我们现在确实在做，所以
that is one way you can programmatically
这是您可以编程方式之一
control what is written ice about this
控制关于此的书面意见
is you can have different computations
你可以有不同的计算
executing at any given time and you can
在任何给定时间执行，您可以
tailor the needs of those computations
量身定制这些计算的需求
separately without one global setting in
单独进行，没有一个全局设置
your application so that can work really
您的应用程序才能真正起作用
well for you depending on what you're
对你来说好取决于你
trying to do well let's go a little
努力做好，让我们走一点
further to talk about some ways in which
进一步讨论一些方法
we should really be very careful again
我们应该再次非常小心
because we can really mess up things if
因为如果我们真的可以搞砸
you're not very careful so let's switch
你不是很小心所以让我们切换
gears to a little bit of a slightly
齿轮稍微
different problem here I want to be able
我想在这里有不同的问题
to run things faster but when parallel
更快地运行但并行时
may not be really a good thing to do so
这样做可能并不是一件真正的好事
to understand this I mentioned that you
了解这一点，我提到你
have to be very careful the number of
必须非常小心
threads to illustrate this point allow
线程来说明这一点允许
me to bring in a little code here and
我在这里输入一些代码，
I'm gonna go ahead and bring in a
我要去带一个
concurrent example right here and in
在此处和此处的并发示例
this case I'll go ahead and say in this
在这种情况下，我会继续说
let's say this is a computation that's
假设这是一个计算
what I want to call as and I'm going to
我想称呼为什么，我将要
bring in this little computation code
引入这个小的计算代码
and what I'm doing is a pure example
我在做的只是一个纯粹的例子
trivial example when you call compute it
调用计算时的简单示例
opens up to four loops and performs
打开多达四个循环并执行
square root operation on it and then of
然后对其进行平方根运算
course out here I totally sum find the
当然在这里我总和找到
sum of all the square root of all those
所有这些的平方根之和
values in short it's a computation
简而言之，这是一种计算
intensive operation I'm just throwing
我只是在进行密集操作
this through these loops and running
通过这些循环并运行
them in in in in sequence as you can see
如您所见，它们按顺序排列
right here this is pretty much a
在这里，这几乎是一个
sequential code how much time is it
顺序代码需要多少时间
gonna run to do this
要跑去做
work so I'm gonna just run the
工作，所以我要运行
sequential code and I don't know it's
顺序代码，我不知道它是
going to take maybe a few seconds to run
可能要花几秒钟才能运行
I don't want it to be too long and it's
我不希望它太长，这是
going to come back and give us a result
会回来给我们结果
with the very end of this so you can see
最后，这样你就可以看到
that it's actually taking a little bit
实际上需要一点时间
time to execute it but I want to make
是时候执行它了，但我想
this faster I want to run this faster I
我想跑得更快
forgot to say time on this I apologize
忘了说时间，对此我表示歉意
so I'm gonna run this now but I would I
所以我现在要运行这个，但是我会
don't want to wait for it but when it is
不想等待它，但是当它是
done it's gonna tell us how much time
完成它会告诉我们多少时间
it's gonna take in the meantime let's
在此期间，让我们
run this in parallel so I'm gonna go
并行运行它，所以我要去
ahead and say dart parallel right here
前面说在这里平行飞镖
and what is it going to do now it's
现在该怎么办
gonna run in parallel sure but how many
要并行运行，但有多少
threads as many threads as a number of
线程数与
course on my machine because I'm using
在我的机器上学习课程，因为我正在使用
the default settings so we are hoping
默认设置，所以我们希望
this will be faster than the sequential
这将比顺序的要快
run which actually took about 13 seconds
运行实际上花费了大约13秒
that's what it says right about 13 14
这就是大约13 14的意思
seconds just keep that in mind
请记住几秒钟
so I want to go ahead and run this in
所以我想继续进行
parallel now and see how much time it's
现在平行运行，看看有多少时间
going to take so now that it's parallel
现在要采取的措施是平行的
multiple threads are gonna run this hey
多个线程会运行这个嘿
notice that we finished in about three
请注意，我们在大约三分钟内完成了
seconds instead of 13 seconds I would
秒，而不是13秒
say that's pretty decent because we made
说这很不错，因为我们做了
it faster but now I'm going to be that
它更快，但现在我要成为那个
that person who is jealous I'm sorry I
那个嫉妒的人我很抱歉
want more of this so I'm gonna run this
需要更多这样的东西，所以我要运行这个
config with a thousand threads why not I
用一千个线程配置为什么不我
have the power to create threads so I'm
有能力创建线程，所以我
gonna go ahead and create those threads
继续创建这些线程
after all we went from three seconds and
毕竟我们走了三秒钟
what does it say in this case of course
在这种情况下，它怎么说
I forgot to do the time again so we'll
我忘了再做一次，所以我们会
do the time on this and what does it
花点时间做些什么
take to run this after three seconds
三秒钟后运行
that it took earlier it took about four
之前花了大约四个
seconds as you can see so it actually
如您所见，实际上是几秒钟
did not take less time it in this case
在这种情况下并没有花费更少的时间
actually took more time
实际上花了更多时间
I've actually worked on projects where a
我实际上已经在项目中
sequential code takes an hour to run the
顺序代码需要一个小时才能运行
parallel code did not finish even after
并行代码甚至没有完成
we came back from lunch and we really
我们从午餐回来，我们真的
had a very long lunch actually so the
实际上吃了很长的午餐，所以
point really is you could really mess up
关键是你真的可能搞砸了
things we're not careful with it so
我们对此不小心的事情
there's a reason for controlling that
有控制的理由
one other thing I want to quickly
我想快速做的另一件事
mention here is we really have to
这里提到的是我们真的必须
understand that certain things may not
了解某些事情可能不会
go in our favor with parallel so to
并行地支持我们，以便
understand this let's take a slightly
了解这一点，让我们稍微
different example but before I go into
不同的例子，但在我进入之前
the example let's kind of talk a little
这个例子让我们有点说话
broadly
宽广地
couple of things you need to ask before
您需要先问几件事
you turn your code into parallel the
您将代码转换为并行
first question is do you have a lot of
第一个问题是你有很多吗
data to really process many parallel is
真正要处理许多并行的数据是
an answer in that case do you have a lot
那样的话你有很多吗
of work to do
工作要做
maybe parallel is an answer in that case
在这种情况下也许并行是一个答案
imagine you have two children at your
想象你有两个孩子
home and you're running out of sugar
回家，你的糖快用完了
so you yell out saying hey I'm running
所以你大声说嘿我在跑步
out of sugar go get some sugar from the
从糖中取出一些糖
neighbor one kid goes out to get that
邻居一个孩子出去得到那个
you know get into the bicycle so he can
你知道骑自行车，所以他可以
he or she can write to the neighbor the
他或她可以给邻居写信
other kid jumps the fence do you know
其他孩子跳篱笆吗
which kid is going to get you the sugar
哪个孩子会给你糖
really quickly the one that jumps the
真的很快就跳了
fence obviously because the neighbor is
围栏显然是因为邻居
just a neighbor right across from the
只是对面的邻居
fence you don't have to go through a lot
栅栏，你不必经历很多
of effort to get there jumping the fence
努力到达那儿跳过篱笆
quick on the other hand you say I really
另一方面，你说我真的
need a bag of rice go to the store or
需要一袋米去商店或
five kilometres away and get it well one
五公里远，好起来一
kid jumps the fence the other one takes
孩子跳栅栏，另一个人带
the bicycle the one that jumps of the
自行车跳的
fence is probably going to end up in
栅栏可能最终会在
jail
监狱
so you don't want that kind of behavior
所以你不想要那种行为
at the point so you really have to ask
在这一点上，所以你真的必须问
the question how much distance I'm a
这个问题我有多远
covering how much data am i processing
涵盖我正在处理多少数据
what is the intensity of the task do
任务的强度是多少
always benchmarking oh by the way I
一直以我为基准哦
never trust benchmark anybody else
永远不要相信别人的基准
creates it's gotta be something I do for
创建它一定是我要做的事情
my project with the relevant information
我的项目以及相关信息
on my teams and that's one of the
在我的团队中，这是其中之一
reasons why I never trust anybody is
我从来不相信任何人的原因是
much more a benchmark including my own
一个基准，包括我自己的基准
when I switched between project status
当我在项目状态之间切换时
so you have to really try it out and see
所以你必须真的尝试一下看看
if it makes sense but having said that
如果有道理但话虽如此
let me give you one other example I want
让我再举一个我想要的例子
to quickly point out here I want to take
快速指出我想带的
an example here of let's say working
举个例子，说工作
with a collection of people so in this
与一群人，所以在这个
example what I want to do here is I want
我想在这里做的事就是
to take this create people let's say
拿这个创造人们来说
create let's say create people list over
假设创建人员列表超过
here and I got a bunch of people on my
在这里，我有一堆人
hand and with different names different
手和不同的名字不同
agender and different age but what I
性别和年龄不同，但我
want to do here is the following I want
我想在这里做的是以下我想要的
to say in here given the stree a people
在这里说给一个人一个街
collection so we'll say create people I
集合，所以我们说创造人我
want to say dart stream then I'll say
想说飞镖流然后我会说
filter given a person get me the person
给人一个过滤器，让我得到这个人
dart let's say get age is greater than
dart让我们说年龄大于
25 well I want somebody who is older
25好，我想要一个年长的人
25 then I'll say filter person and I
25然后我会说过滤人和我
would say person dot get gender and I'll
会说人点变得性别，我会
say in this case gender dart female and
说在这种情况下性别飞镖女和
then I would say dot map given a person
那我说点地图给一个人
give me the person that get name name of
给我取名字的人
the person if you will and then finally
这个人，如果你愿意，然后最后
what I'm gonna do here is to say you
我要在这里说的是你
know maybe convert it to an uppercase so
知道也许将其转换为大写
let's go ahead and say string to
让我们继续说
uppercase
大写
so in this case of course what I have
所以在这种情况下我当然有
done is I've taken the first person
完成是我已经采取了第一人称
older than 25 who is a female got the
25岁以上的女性
name and transformed the first uppercase
命名并转换第一个大写
but then I say in the end find first
但最后我说先找到
and I'm wondering Who am I going to find
我想知道我要找到谁
really and then of course our else will
真的，然后我们当然会
say no one found so I want to just print
说找不到人，所以我只想打印
this and see what the output looks like
看看输出是什么样子
in this particular case so let's output
在这种情况下，让我们输出
this right here and see what we get out
就在这里，看看我们得到了什么
of this so in this example of course I'm
所以在这个例子中我
gonna round this little code and it says
要四舍五入这个小代码，它说
Paulo
保罗
well sure it's Paulo because if you go
好吧，那是Paulo，因为如果你去
through the list it's the ordered
通过列表是有序的
collection and Serra and sarra are not
收集和塞拉和撒拉不是
older than 25 Bob it's not tada Paulo is
比鲍勃（Bob）年龄大25岁
the first person older than 25 and he's
第一个年龄超过25岁的人
also female so we got that but the
也是女性，所以我们得到了，但
question is what we did we put in I'll
问题是我们要做的是
come back to that in just a minute
再过一分钟再说
but let's go back and run the score
但是让我们回去运行比分
several several times just real quick
好几次好快
here let's go ahead and say run dart SH
在这里，让我们继续说“运行飞镖SH”
just once
就一次
it says Paulo but I want to run this
它说Paulo但我要运行这个
many many many times so here we go and
很多很多很多次，所以我们在这里去
I'm gonna keep running this you know
我要继续运行这个，你知道
several several times so I could keep
几次，所以我可以保持
going in a number of times right here
在这里走了好几次
and I say run this all and it's going to
我说全部运行，这将
be repeatedly Paulo isn't it doesn't
反复保罗是不是
matter how many times I run I know
不管我跑步多少次，我都知道
running this and it's not a proof of it
运行它，这不是它的证明
but just trust me it's gonna be the same
但只要相信我，一切都会一样
as many times as you run it but on the
运行多次，但在
other hand there is also a function
另一方面还有一个功能
called find any
叫找到任何
what does find any say I don't care who
会发现什么说我不在乎谁
it is just find one of them well find
只是找到其中之一而已
any will give us one of them if it's
如果有的话，任何人都会给我们一个
available so in this case when I go back
可用，所以在这种情况下，我回去时
and run this what am I gonna get it
并运行这个我会得到什么
turns out it's Paulo - not fair why
原来是Paulo-为什么不公平
because it's sequential II executing and
因为它是按顺序执行的II
it because it's sequential the first one
它是因为它是第一个顺序的
is always there any as well right okay
总是在那里也好吧
that's kind of easy to see but let's get
这很容易看到，但让我们开始吧
back out now put it back and find first
退回现在放回去，先找到
again but in this case I'm gonna turn
再一次，但在这种情况下，我要转身
this in
这个在
dark parallel well what's going to
黑暗平行好怎么办
happen now remember this is an ordered
现在发生，记住这是有序的
collection and remember we talked about
收藏，还记得我们谈论过
certain methods being ordered in the
某些方法在
past remember that we talked about for
过去记得我们谈论过
each ordered
每个命令
well fine first is one of those guys it
很好，首先是那些家伙之一
doesn't have the name ordered in it but
没有名称顺序，但
it's going to impose ordering in the
它会在
very end so you're going to do this in
非常结束，所以您将在其中执行此操作
parallel awesome but unfortunately
并行很棒但不幸的是
though you're gonna do this in parallel
尽管您将并行执行此操作
which is great but what are you gonna
很棒，但是你会怎么做
get you're gonna get Paulo all the time
得到你会一直得到Paulo
you better do right because you want the
你最好做对，因为你想要
first one the ordering is important to
首先，订购对
you let's see if that's true let's go
你让我们看看那是真的吧
ahead and run this and see it's Paulo
继续并运行它，看看是Paulo
every single time again that's not a
再一次不是
proof just because I ran it 70 times it
证明只是因为我跑了70次
doesn't mean it's correct again trust me
并不代表再次正确，请相信我
on that search on this but what if I
在这个搜索上，但是如果我
turn this into a find any on the other
把这个变成另一个
hand and run this code now
立即运行并运行此代码
well this time notice it is still Paulo
好吧，这次通知它仍然是Paulo
but I'm hoping it'll be different
但我希望情况会有所不同
sometime okay it's not in my favor this
有时候好吧，这对我不利
is that this is the this is the peril of
是这是这的危险
a demo isn't it but hopefully at some
演示不是吗，但希望有一些演示
point you will run this enough number of
点，您将运行足够数量的
times and okay so again trust me on this
好的，所以再次相信我
one too right so what what is it
一个太正确了，那是什么
oh it's positive when the answer here
哦，这是肯定的答案
you're saying well okay you know there
你说的很好，知道了
are no other feet
没有别的脚
I blame it on you okay thank you so
我怪你了好吧，谢谢
let's make it as you know let's say Oh
让它如您所愿让我们说哦
Jill what is Jill Jill my friend let's
Jill什么是Jill Jill我的朋友让我们
just make Jill older okay so there we go
只是让吉尔变老就好，所以我们去了
so all right try this one more time this
所以可以再尝试一次
time I didn't even notice about good
时间我什至没有注意到好
good cats there you go thank you all
好猫，你去那里，谢谢大家
right yeah thank you for for debugging
是的，谢谢您的调试
that my faith in paid programming was
我对付费编程的信念是
just restored all right so right there
刚好恢复就好了
we got the result the case in point
我们得到了正确的结果
right but of course if I go back to this
是的，但是如果我回到这个问题上
and say this is going to be fine the
并说这会很好的
first on the other hand you will it
另一方面，你会的
better be polished trying this time
这次最好擦亮
right so in this case of course it'll be
对，所以在这种情况下，当然
the exact same value every single time
每次完全相同的值
you're with me so far but there is one
到目前为止，你和我在一起，但是有一个
thing I love about streams and that is
我喜欢溪流的一件事是
laziness well let's talk about that real
懒惰好吧，让我们谈谈真正的
quick let's go ahead and remove this
快速，让我们继续删除它
parallel for a minute let's just do fine
并行一分钟，让我们做的很好
first if you will and I want to know who
首先，如果您愿意，我想知道谁
all I'm gonna talk to here's our Jill
我要说的就是我们的吉尔
who just got older but we have Paula who
刚长大，但我们有宝拉
is older than 30 to 25 but who am I
年龄超过30至25岁，但我是谁
going to talk to repeatedly if I go to
如果我去的话，要反复交谈
the person class right here in the gate
门口的人班
age I'm gonna print out right here I'm
我要在这里打印的年龄
gonna say name while sorry get aged up
不好意思长大的时候会说名字
and then plus name and then of course
然后加上名称，然后当然
I'm also going to come on name and I'm
我也要出名，我
also going to output in this case I
在这种情况下我也要输出
wanted the gender as well didn't I so
我也想要性别，不是吗
I'm going to go ahead and ask for that
我要去问那个
to be printed right here too so I'll go
也要在这里打印，所以我去
ahead and say this is going to be get
向前说这将成为现实
gender and print that information okay
性别并打印该信息就可以了
that's great so far I'm doing two
到目前为止很好，我正在做两个
sequential e as you can see in here so
如您在此处看到的顺序e
I'm gonna go ahead and run this code and
我将继续运行此代码，然后
the beauty I'm just gonna do it once so
我会做一次的美丽
I'm gonna run this code in sequence and
我要按顺序运行此代码，
as you would expect it did not touch
如您所料，它没有碰到
anyone other than after Paula make sense
除了宝拉之后，其他任何人都说得通
right because it's lazy it says I don't
对，因为它很懒，它说我不
need to run this fast I'm gonna just
需要快速运行，我只是
process it Oh Sara Bob Paula today I got
哦，今天我得到了Sara Bob Paula
my result I never have to talk to anyone
我的结果是我永远不必与任何人交谈
besides Paula
除了宝拉
never touches Paul Jack Jack and Jill on
永远不会碰到Paul Jack Jack和Jill
the other hand I'm gonna go in and say a
另一方面，我要进去说一个
dot parallel right now now what's it
点平行现在是什么
going to do it says whoa look at this
要做它说哇看这个
let's get the business we got data in
让我们开始获取数据的业务
front of us to do work and it's gonna be
我们前面要做工作，它将成为
on fire isn't it and as a result what is
着火了吗，结果是什么
it result going to be in the very end
结果将在最后
still Paula but it's not going to be
仍然是宝拉，但事实并非如此
lazy like the way we thought it is and
像我们认为的那样懒惰
notice a lot more work being done let me
注意到还有很多工作要做
summarize this in a slightly different
总结一下
example let's say I was just hanging
举例来说，我刚上吊
around here and I was going around
在这里，我正在四处走动
what's your name sir Tom Thomas I let's
汤姆·托马斯先生，你叫什么名字，我让
say I left my phone next to Thomas right
说我把手机留在托马斯旁边
so here's what I could do I could say
所以这就是我能说的
excuse me is my phone next to you he
对不起，我是你旁边的手机，他
says no excuse me' in mephone x2 he says
说不对不起，我在手机x2中说
no is my phone next to you
不，我的手机在你旁边吗
thank you he said yes and so how much
谢谢你，他说是的，那么多少
ever did I take three units how much
我曾经拿过三个单位多少钱
time did I take three units of time and
我花了三个时间单位
I got my phone after that but that
那之后我拿了电话，但是那
required a little bit more effort here's
需要更多的努力
something else I could do right I could
我可以做的其他事
just say into this room saying folks do
只是说进入这个房间，说人们
do me a favor please
请帮我一个忙
here's my phone next to you how much
这是我旁边的手机多少钱
time would it take for me to get the
我要花些时间
result one unit of time how many people
结果一个时间单位有多少人
did i disturb hundreds of people so the
我打扰了数百个人，所以
good news I got the result faster the
好消息，我更快地得到了结果
bad news I bothered everyone good news I
坏消息我困扰所有人
don't care so that is the beauty of this
不在乎，这就是这个的美丽
so that is the model here right the
所以这是这里的模型
model here is I don't mind throwing more
这里的模型是我不介意抛出更多
hardware at this problem with the hope
硬件在这个问题上有希望
of getting the result faster hope that
更快获得结果的希望
was useful thank you
很有用，谢谢
[Applause]
[掌声]